Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Albion, Calhoun County, Mich.) records, 1839-1957
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Albion, Calhoun County, Mich.) records 1839-1957
First Presbyterian Church (Albion, Calhoun County, Mich.)
1 microfilms
3 linear feet
86800 Ba 2; Ba microcopy
Church established in 1837; board of trustees minutes, records of women’s organizations; and other church records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is on deposit from the church (donor no. 1292 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church of Albion, Michigan was established in 1837.
The records is comprised of the following series: History / Background; Board of Trustees minutes; Correspondence; Annual reports; Financial records; Women's organizations; Other records; and Microfilm records.
Subjects:
Albion (Calhoun County, Mich.); Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.--Michigan--Albion (Calhoun County); Women--Religious life--Michigan--Albion (Calhoun County); Women--Michigan--Albion (Calhoun County)--Societies and clubs.; First Presbyterian Church (Albion, Calhoun County, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- History / Background
  - Papers concerning the history of the First Presbyterian Church delivered on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the church 1887 (Box 1)
- Board of Trustees
  - Minutes
    - 1911-1916, 1 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1929-1953, 1 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1953-1956, 1 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1929-1938 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1929-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1957 (Box 1)
- Annual reports
  - 1936-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1951-1954 (Box 1)
- Financial
  - Financial records 1933-1937, undated (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's books 1893-1901, 7 volumes (Box 1)
- Women's organizations
  - Ladies Aid society
    - Miscellaneous papers
      - 1927-1928 (Box 2)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 2)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 2)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 2)
      - 1931-1932 (Box 2)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 2)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 2)
      - 1934-1935 (Box 2)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 2)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 2)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 2)
      - 1939-1941 (Box 2)
      - 1941-1943 (Box 2)
      - 1943-1948 (Box 2)
    - Minutes
      - 1932-1946 (Box 2)
      - 1946-1951 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's books
      - 1928-1934 (Box 2)
      - 1935-1949 (Box 2)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - Women's Association
    - Records 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Deaconesses records
    - Papers 1948-1955 (Box 3)
    - Record book 1918-1921, 1 volumes (Box 3)
  - Women's Missionary Society
    - Record books
      - 1882-1888 (Box 3)
      - 1914-1920 (Box 3)
      - 1926-1929 (Box 3)
- Other records
  - Church school papers 1952-1957, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Sunday School teachers record book 1935-1947, 1 volumes (Box 3)
  - Pulpit Committee 1953-1954, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Weekly bulletins 1954 (Box 3)
  - Financial reports 1954 (Box 3)
  - Membership records 1929-1939 (Box 3)
  - Printed materials 1935-1938 (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea 1930-1953 (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea 1954-1957 (Box 3)
  - Book of certificates of demission and reception, 1 volumes (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1936, 1 volumes (Box 3)
- Microfilm records, negative microfilm
  - Music fund accounts 1896-1902 (Reel 1)
  - Session minutes August 1902-March 1904 (Reel 1)
  - Session minutes 1884-1926 (Reel 1)
  - Session minutes 1926-1954 (Reel 1)
  - Minutes of the First Presbyterian Church Society 1911-1935 (Reel 1)
  - Church register 1839-1937 (Reel 1)